- [Instructor] When your app starts to grow,
state management needs to be handled very effectively.
Now, we want to focus on making the code
more flexible and more maintainable,
with the help of another hook: useReducer.
useReducer is an alternative to useState
that provides a more powerful and a more flexible way
of managing the state in your components.
It is especially useful for handling complex state logic
as it allows to separate the state management logic
from your components,
making the code easier to understand, easier to maintain,
and to test.
And so, useReducer accept a reducer function
and one initialState as parameters.
Then, it returns an array
with the current states and a dispatch method.
So, let's see one example with useReducer.
Until now, we have created and kept the state
at the top level of the root components app.
Instead, we would like to manage the state
in a separate location,
so let's do that with useReducer.
We're going to replace all the state variables
with useReducer.
So, we're going to start by importing useReducer.
You're going to add it through the scope right here
of your app.gs.
Let's go back to the root components,
and right here, at the top level,
you're going to call useReducer.
It's going to return an array.
And as parameters, you're going to have one reducer function.
So, for now, it's not existing,
so we're going to replace with an anonymous function,
and one empty object as initialState.
Then, it's going to return a state objects
and a dispatch method.
So next, we want to remove all the state variables
that we have created with useState,
so let's do that like this.
But stop. Not just yet.
First, you want to refactor the app
and move all the logic in a reducer function.
So, let's go back.
We're going to first create a new function, reducer.
So, we're just going to leave it as is for now.
And also, we're going to create one initialState,
an empty object that's going to hold the initialState.
So, we're going to replace here with initialState
and reducer for the function reducer.
And so, the role of the function reducer
will be to return a new state,
and after that, all the data will be handled
through the useReducer only.
And so, the component will be able to read the state,
the data,
by reading from the state object like so.
And so, useReducer is a preferred solution
when the business logic of your app is starting to grow
and become more complex.
The goals are to separate the logic from the presentation,
and move all the business logic
in a separate function called reducer
that we are yet to complete and to implement,
and this is what we're doing next.